## Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom +44 7487 553781 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

### PROFILE

Self-motivated software developer with six years of experience in the field and four years of experience in Java development. Motivated to participate as a team player and develop well-tested applications using a continuous delivery approach. I highly enjoy carrying out profound research and learning about new technologies, alongside looking for ways to improve my work.

### Programming Skills

- Languages: Java, TypeScript Technologies: Spring Framework, Angular, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito
- Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Jenkins, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis

### EXPERIENCE

• Monese London, United Kingdom

Technical Lead Engineer Jul 2020 - Present

 $\circ~$  As a part of the Payments team, I was leading and refactoring a monolith into a single responsibility

microservice.

• Monese London, United Kingdom
Software Engineer Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

- Reduced costs by systematically improving software performance and decreasing operating costs. For one application, its monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.
- Increased revenue by identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a solution for a single customer led to the identification of a significant gap in profit.
- As a part of the Pricing team, delivered business priorities by completing a new, annual pricing functionality
  on-time and without any significant issues. Additionally, I led research on breaking a monolithic application
  into a single responsibility microservice.
- As a part of the Joint Accounts team, I designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese
Software Engineer

Tallinn, Estonia
Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- As a part of the Smart Transactions team, I improved the scalability of micro-services by separating the read and write operation of the database.
- $\circ$  Successfully migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. As a result, the average response time decreased from 60ms to 5ms.
- $\circ\,$  Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- As a part of the Recurring Payments team, I designed and developed a micro-service with a test coverage of up to 80%.

• Codeborne

Software Developer

Tallinn, Estonia

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- As a part of the Banking team, I advocated for clean, robust, and maintainable code while promoting through code reviews, pair programming, and test-driven development.
- Increased the team's productivity by sharing my peers' development tricks.
- Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.

• Knowit

Software Developer

Tallinn, Estonia

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

- Employee of the Q4, 2016.
- Developed a full-stack, web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.

# EDUCATION

## • Tallinn University

Estonia

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (BSc); Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

- o Bachelor's Thesis "The Development of a Self-study Web Application Using Angular and Spring Boot"
- Achievement stipend
- $\circ$  Specialisation stipend